MARSHALL MILEY

Golden, CO

Phone: 601-594-6591 | Email: miley.marshall.b@gmail.com LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/mileymarshall/ GitHub: https://github.com/m-miley Portfolio: https://m-miley.github.io/portfolio/

Summary

Enthusiastic Data Analyst with a strong background in mathematics and a passion for accuracy, aptitude for clear communication, penchant for complex problem solving, and drive for developing actionable insights to cultivate success. Talent for converting complicated data into palatable stories.

Technical Skills

Excel - Functions, Pivot Tables, Visualizations, Analysis, VBA Scripting

Databases - PostgreSQL, SQLite, SQLAlchemy, MongoDB, SAP

Languages - SQL, Python, JavaScript, CSS, HTML, R basics

<u>Libraries</u> - Pandas, Matplotlib, Flask, sklearn, tf, NumPy, Plotly.js, D3.js, Leaflet.js, tidyverse, ggplot2 BI Visualization - Tableau

Data - JSON, GeoJSON, AWS - RDS, S3 Buckets, Pyspark, Hadoop

Tools - GitHub, VSCode, pgAdmin 4, Jupyter Notebook, Quick DBD, RStudio, Google Colab

Statistics - Descriptive, Inferential, Machine Learning

Projects

Lyft - Bay Wheels | https://github.com/markm3690/Baywheels_SF

Queried SQL database to analyze data from ~5 million rides spanning 2.5 years to present suggestions for distribution, maintenance, and bike models based on user type, trip length, dock capacity, and frequency of travel. PostgreSQL, pgAdmin 4, Excel, PowerPoint Presentation.

NASS Honey Bees | https://public.tableau.com/app/profile/marshall3619/viz/NASSHoneyBees/HoneyBee With Tableau, I constructed and published an analysis from a Honey Bee data set provided by NASS. Implemented detailed data visualization strategies to create two interactive dashboards tracking health and economy. Culminated in a 10 minute peer presentation using Story mode in Tableau.

Credit Risk Analysis | https://github.com/m-miley/Credit_Risk_Analysis

Machine Learning Analysis to predict risk associated with loan status. Logistic Regression, Sampling Techniques, and Ensemble Learning. Preprocessing techniques applied for cleaning. Evaluation of Classification Report shows sensitivity score of 91% for correctly classifying high risk loans.

Education

University of Denver Denver, CO

2022

Data Analytics & Visualization Boot Camp Certificate

24-week intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in Excel, VBA, Python, R, Web Scraping, HTML, CSS, JavaScript, SQL Databases, Tableau, Big Data, and Machine Learning.

General Assembly London, UK

2022

Data Analytics Certificate

10-week program focused on completing thorough analysis on a range of data sets from superstore to rideshare, government, and science. Skills in Excel, SQL, Tableau

L'institut de Touraine Tours, France

French Language Study

Immersive and Intensive 8-week study of French Language and culture.

Mississippi College Clinton, MS

2008

B.S. Mathematics

Emphasis on complex problem solving and applied mathematics. Calculus I-IV, statistics, modern geometry, topology, linear algebra, discrete mathematics, modern algebra, differential equations, trigonometry, physics, chemistry. Business minor. Cum Laude, Honors, Pi Mu Epsilon.

Experience

Assistant Store Manager

2017-2022

Natural Grocers by Vitamin Cottage Golden, CO

Manage a store with 34 employees. Persistent, proactive, and daily strive for operational excellence. Boost morale through daily huddles and monthly meetings to maximize employee retention, job satisfaction, and efficiency. Focus and drive to accomplish sales goals, meet deadlines, merchandise product, and display promotional materials effectively. Scheduling, Recruiting, Leadership, Training, Mentoring, HR Best Practices, Conflict Resolution, Conference calls, Sales calls, Inventory Management, QRG's and much more! Daily use of SAP to track and manage inventory, reconcile P.O.s, monitor sales, and improve operations. Performed monthly analysis of top and bottom sellers using BEX. Improved sales 9-30% over previous year in produce department and 4-8% store-wide through merchandising, accurate ordering, and world class customer service. Region's best monthly performer for meeting COGS goal. Noted for reliability and work ethic. Exceeded expectations. Recognized for exceptional people skills resulting in robust customer loyalty. Praised for team building and motivational skills. Promoted within two months of hiring and up for promotion again the following year.

Horticulturist 2016-2017

Harmony Gardens Golden, CO

Successful full season growth and propagation for organic fruit and vegetables. Engineered irrigation systems and crop layout designs. Organic composting, fertilizing, and pest management best practices lead to abundant and delicious produce. Harvesting, communication, and distribution of yield. Promote community involvement and hype. Focus on building healthy soil.

LTP Trail Crew Leader 2014-2015

Green Mountain Club Waterbury Center, VT

Build and maintain Vermont trail systems. Manage food, team, and supplies. Lead volunteer crews on spike camps, 4 nights/5 days a week. Project development, management, and leadership. Tracking time management, safety assessments, lead training activities and wilderness ethics discussion.

Lead Technician 2012-2014

Polaris Laboratories Salt Lake City, Utah

Lead night crew to test and analyze oil samples according to rigorous scientific testing. ICP-AES, Acid/Base titrations, Viscosity, Particle Count, Particle Quantifier, Brix, etc. Through managing time and troubleshooting equipment, I ensured the team met test quota while confirming accuracy.

References

Available Upon Request

2010